<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>inadequate futures</title>
    <link>https://inadeqtfuturs.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on inadequate futures</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 16 Jan 2018 18:14:39 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://inadeqtfuturs.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>[011 - spring writing class]</title>
      <link>https://inadeqtfuturs.github.io/post/011-spring-writing-class/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jan 2018 18:14:39 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://inadeqtfuturs.github.io/post/011-spring-writing-class/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This week, I begin teaching a core writing class centered around digital composition and contemporary issues (broadly conceived). Having not taught this course since Fall of 2015, the syllabus and schedule went through a nearly wholesale rewrite. Even now, I wonder if it&amp;rsquo;s doing the work of tracing conversations about technology and the present that I envisioned it doing. You can find a copy of the course schedule &lt;a href=&#34;https://inadeqtfuturs.github.io/syllabus/ucwr110/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[010 - review of Stacy Alaimo&#39;s &lt;i&gt;Exposed&lt;/i&gt;]</title>
      <link>https://inadeqtfuturs.github.io/post/010-alaimo-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jan 2018 17:49:11 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://inadeqtfuturs.github.io/post/010-alaimo-review/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://inadeqtfuturs.github.io/images/cover-exposed.png&#34; class=&#34;cover&#34;/&gt;I recently reviewed Stacy Alaimo&amp;rsquo;s &lt;i&gt;Exposed&lt;/i&gt; over at &lt;a href=&#39;http://asapjournal.com/&#39;&gt;ASAP/J&lt;/a&gt;. The review focuses on Alaimo&amp;rsquo;s utilization of art and activism that foregrounds the trans-corporeal nature of subjectivity and embodiment. By interweaving geo- and biopolitical concerns into her theorization of the anthropocene, Alaimo&amp;rsquo;s work &amp;lsquo;reorients attention to the seemingly mundane political and aesthetic practices of co-inhabitation that shape humans and their environments.&amp;rsquo; You can find the review &lt;a href=&#39;http://asapjournal.com/stacy-alaimos-exposed-environmental-politics-and-pleasures-in-posthuman-times-alex-christie/&#39;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[009 - smooth talk]</title>
      <link>https://inadeqtfuturs.github.io/post/009-smooth-talk/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Nov 2017 10:37:59 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://inadeqtfuturs.github.io/post/009-smooth-talk/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;wide&#34; src=&#34;https://inadeqtfuturs.github.io/images/smooth-talk.png&#34;/&gt;The good folks over at &lt;a href=&#39;http://reallifemag.com/&#39;&gt;Real Life Mag&lt;/a&gt; were kind enough to let me write about Grammarly, fungible subjectivity, and becoming no one. The essay explores our capitulation to optimization/augmentation apps, which ultimately subordinate content to form, effectively rendering the user as anyone &amp;ndash; the faceless subject of neoliberalism. You can find it &lt;a href=&#39;http://reallifemag.com/smooth-talk/&#39;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[008 - the novel as inhuman]</title>
      <link>https://inadeqtfuturs.github.io/post/008-novel-as-inhuman/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Sep 2017 10:57:47 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://inadeqtfuturs.github.io/post/008-novel-as-inhuman/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My current project/chapter has me returning to Mark Z. Danielewski&amp;rsquo;s work, a novelist who&amp;rsquo;s been with me since I first thought about teaching, and latter became an important fixture for how I think about literature, and then, again, latter, became an even &lt;i&gt;more&lt;/i&gt; important figure for how I think about ethics, (non)humans, and so much more. Although the chapter is specifically interested in inter-weaving Danielewski&amp;rsquo;s most recent set of novels, collectively known as &lt;i&gt;The &lt;font color=&#34;#f9b9d2&#34;&gt;Familiar&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/i&gt;, into contemporary posthumanism, figuring &lt;i&gt;The &lt;font color=&#34;#f9b9d2&#34;&gt;Familiar&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/i&gt; as another resource for theorizing relationality among (non)humans, it&amp;rsquo;s also given me a chance to revisit his work as a whole. Specifically, I&amp;rsquo;m looking at some of the &amp;lsquo;paratextual&amp;rsquo; (if you can call it that) projects surrounding &lt;i&gt;The &lt;font color=&#34;#f9b9d2&#34;&gt;Familiar&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/i&gt; including a talk that later became an article called &amp;lsquo;Parable No. 9: The Hopeless Animal and the End of Nature.&amp;rsquo; Given in Cologne, Germany in the Fall of 2010, the talk catalyzed my interest in posthumanism, actor network theory, and speculative realism (though I&amp;rsquo;ve largely abandoned the latter two in favor of the former), and continues to inform how I think about hope and our relation to animals. By that same token, I&amp;rsquo;m hoping that &amp;lsquo;Parable No. 9&amp;rsquo; will offer insight into Danielewski&amp;rsquo;s novels&amp;mdash;there&amp;rsquo;s clearly cross-contamination&amp;mdash;as well as provide fodder for positioning his work among other posthuman theorists.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[007 - &#39;towrads an intra-active ethics&#39;]</title>
      <link>https://inadeqtfuturs.github.io/post/007-intra-active-ethics/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jun 2017 11:23:23 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://inadeqtfuturs.github.io/post/007-intra-active-ethics/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This summer, i was lucky enough to participate in the inaugural modern and contemporary studies initiative summer institute at penn state. Necessarily germinal, the paper i presented gestures the first dissertation chapter i&amp;rsquo;m working on, tentatively titled &amp;lsquo;the subject after postmodernism: Barad, Levinas, and Intra-Active Ethics&amp;rsquo;. A pdf of the presentation can be found below.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[006 - &lt;i&gt;That Winter the Wolf Came&lt;/i&gt;, autonomy, and climate]</title>
      <link>https://inadeqtfuturs.github.io/post/006-winter-the-wolf-came/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jun 2017 11:43:17 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://inadeqtfuturs.github.io/post/006-winter-the-wolf-came/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://inadeqtfuturs.github.io/images/cover-winter.jpg&#34; class=&#34;wide&#34; /&gt;
Juliana Spahr&amp;rsquo;s &lt;i&gt;That Winter the Wolf Came&lt;/i&gt; offers solace in a moment of ecological anxiety and disaster. As Trump pulls the U.S. out of the Paris Climate Accord (indeed, a largely symbolic act but with very real ecological, economic, and political ramifications), I&amp;rsquo;m struck by the right&amp;rsquo;s oxymoronic stance on the country&amp;rsquo;s autonomy, or the ability to be autonomous in an age of intensified globalization. It&amp;rsquo;s easy to see the tension between the way the nation-state holds open the door for transnational capital&amp;mdash;i.e. producing fluid borders rather than locking them down and securing the reproduction of a specific citizenry&amp;mdash;and the insistence that somehow the U.S. can stand alone, or dictate the terms by which its borders function. The travel ban, increased racist violence, and the dream of an economy sustained by coal all play into this fantasy of the autonomous nation, and by proxy the autonomous masculine figurehead Trump longs to become.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[005 - &lt;i&gt;Satin Island&lt;/i&gt;]</title>
      <link>https://inadeqtfuturs.github.io/post/005-satin-island/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 May 2017 12:06:04 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://inadeqtfuturs.github.io/post/005-satin-island/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I picked up Tom McCarthy&amp;rsquo;s &lt;i&gt;Satin Island&lt;/i&gt; when I began conceptualizing and planning my dissertation proposal. In an effort to situate my project in whatever &amp;lsquo;the contemporary&amp;rsquo; is, I scoured the web for discussions, syllabi, and articles that focused on the contemporary novel. Reading through &lt;a href=&#34;http://post45.research.yale.edu/&#34;&gt;Post-45&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rsquo;s series of letters from Princeton&amp;rsquo;s &amp;lsquo;The Contemporary&amp;rsquo; conference, McCarthy&amp;rsquo;s novel came into focus as &amp;lsquo;the most discussed (and maligned) novel of the conference,&amp;rsquo; so I decided to give it a shot.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[004 - negativity in Culp]</title>
      <link>https://inadeqtfuturs.github.io/post/004-negativity-in-culp/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 May 2017 08:23:51 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://inadeqtfuturs.github.io/post/004-negativity-in-culp/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m revisiting Andrew Culp&amp;rsquo;s &lt;i&gt;Dark Deleuze&lt;/i&gt; this week. My director suggested the book last summer somewhere between me reading &lt;i&gt;A Thousand Plateaus&lt;/i&gt; and Claire Colebrook&amp;rsquo;s &lt;i&gt;Death of the PostHuman&lt;/i&gt; as an example of a negative version of Deleuze that might help make sense of Colebrook&amp;rsquo;s work. In general, and this is the way I&amp;rsquo;ve always read D&amp;amp;G, &lt;i&gt;TP&lt;/i&gt; has always been this joyous and affirmative text riddled with &amp;lsquo;little monsters&amp;rsquo; for cultivating novel concepts (Culp 1). Each plateau offered something new&amp;mdash;a new concept, methodology, reading. In moments of lucidity (usually while reading and then never again) it feels very portable. Dark Deleuze, by comparison, is very different: &amp;lsquo;Emerging from scholars concerned with the condition of the present, the darkness refashions a revolutionary Deleuze: revolutionary negativity in a world characterized by compulsory happiness, decentralized control, and overexposure&amp;rsquo; (2). This struck me as odd for two reasons: first, all of my work is &amp;lsquo;concerned with the condition of the present,&amp;rsquo; so it seemed odd that I hadn&amp;rsquo;t encountered much of this scholarship. But second, and while I absolutely agree with Culp that the revolutionary concepts offered by Deleuze throughout his corpus&amp;mdash;&amp;lsquo;transversal lines, rhizomatic connections, compositionist networks, complex assemblages, affective experiences, and enchanted objects&amp;rsquo;&amp;mdash;had been largely integrated into public consciousness, it&amp;rsquo;s never occurred to me Deleuze&amp;rsquo;s work had run it&amp;rsquo;s course, cleaved into neoliberal-ese (7).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[003 - emerging from the contemporary]</title>
      <link>https://inadeqtfuturs.github.io/post/003-emerging-from-the-contemporary/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 May 2017 08:28:56 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://inadeqtfuturs.github.io/post/003-emerging-from-the-contemporary/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One thing I&amp;rsquo;m having trouble articulating and working through in the dissertation proposal is the extent to which posthumanism and posthuman subjectivity (interrelated but definitely not coterminous) are either local and site specific or transcendent and ontological. It&amp;rsquo;s clear to me how posthumanism as a discourses arises in the latter half of the 20th century: globalization, transnationalism, and the onset of network culture force us to think differently about how humans are connected. The cellphone (and really, the smartphone) shifts attention away from the human body to the human with(in) a network. The smartphone has become a very literal and felt extension of one kind of cyborg subjectivity. In this way, it&amp;rsquo;s like what Nathan Jurgenson says about identity performance: &amp;lsquo;Social media surely change identity performance. For one, it makes the process more explicit&amp;rsquo; (&amp;rsquo;&lt;a href=&#39;https://thenewinquiry.com/the-disconnectionists/&#39;&gt;The Disconnectionists&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rsquo;). Our imbrication in technology makes explicit something we might have missed before&amp;mdash;how the human and tool are woven together into assemblages or amalgams&amp;mdash;but that then seems ontologically grounded.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[002 - Barad&#39;s &#39;fine details&#39; and/as hyperrealism]</title>
      <link>https://inadeqtfuturs.github.io/post/002-barad-fine-details/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 May 2017 08:40:10 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://inadeqtfuturs.github.io/post/002-barad-fine-details/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Rereading Karen Barad&amp;rsquo;s &lt;i&gt;Meeting the Universe Halfway&lt;/i&gt; is a refreshing reminder of everything I find useful in new materialism and posthumanism. Concerned primarily with how quantum physics might reshape the way we think about matter, agency, and ethics, Barad&amp;rsquo;s work if helpful for articulating where ethical commitments beyond the human, or the human-to-human, might reside. Her reworking of agency is particularly important for her interweaving of the philosophy of physics and poststructural, as she repeats throughout. For Barad, agency is not something humans have, or even particular bodies possess, but rather a distributed enactment across an intra-active assemblage (my word) or apparatus. She argues, &amp;lsquo;Agency is &amp;ldquo;doing&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;being&amp;rdquo; in its intra-activity. It is the enactment of iterative changes of particular practices&amp;mdash;iterative reconfigurings of topological manifolds of spacetimematter relations&amp;mdash;through the dynamics of intra-activity. Agency is about changing possibilities of change entailed in reconfiguring material-discursive apparatuses of bodily production&amp;rsquo; (178). This emphasis on intra-activity reminds us that we (and let&amp;rsquo;s leave this as a slippery signifier) are involved in agency with other matters we tend to not consider imbricated in ourselves. Matter comes to matter through &amp;lsquo;iterative reconfigurings;&amp;rsquo; states that both continually change but also remain the same&amp;mdash;cells perpetually dying and being replaced in bodies human and otherwise, for example. Agency is less a deployment of force here than the tipping over of a system into something else or towards a different state&amp;mdash;a storm tipping over from rain and thunder into a tornado and back again. In a more anthropocentric mode, it&amp;rsquo;s also about admitting that who and what we are is heavily influenced and perhaps even dependent on the matter that surrounds us, both discursive but also (new) material. It&amp;rsquo;s here that I see Barad linking up rather explicitly with poststructuralism, as if to intensify the performative and disciplinary sutures provided by Butler and Foucault.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[001 - blogging the dissertation]</title>
      <link>https://inadeqtfuturs.github.io/post/001-blogging-the-dissertation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Apr 2017 08:43:15 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://inadeqtfuturs.github.io/post/001-blogging-the-dissertation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This blog is a work in progress and performance of writing my dissertation. Today is the first day of writing and research after turning in a draft of the proposal. I imagine this blog taking the form of both sharing relevant research, compressed/compiled for a more general audience, as well as a place to work through the contingencies of academic labor for both graduate and recent graduate students.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>about</title>
      <link>https://inadeqtfuturs.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Apr 2017 08:43:15 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://inadeqtfuturs.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>inadequate futures is an in-progress dissertation by alex christie, a doctoral candidate at Loyola University Chicago who researches and writes about the entanglement of posthumanism and ethics in the present. inadequate futures addresses the relationship between subjectivity and ethics in our contemporary moment, articulating the need to reorient our conceptions of futurity toward an impersonal posthuman subject. By mapping the differences in how we’ve come to describe and theorize subjectivity in the past three decades, inadequate futures theorizes the consequences and possibilities for imagining a future from our contemporary moment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>archives</title>
      <link>https://inadeqtfuturs.github.io/archives/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Feb 2017 08:43:15 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://inadeqtfuturs.github.io/archives/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>course descriptions</title>
      <link>https://inadeqtfuturs.github.io/classes/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Feb 2017 08:43:15 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://inadeqtfuturs.github.io/classes/</guid>
      <description>engl 288: nature in literature - human @ the limit [spring 2017] At the intersection of discussions about intensified global warming, diminishing populations of endangered species, and increasingly perceptive artificial intelligence stands the human, or, at least, the question of the human. In mapping these territories, we necessarily come up against the human and its connection to animals, nature, culture, and technology. While this course focuses on the relationship of human beings and the environment in which they function, as represented in a variety of literary works (the university course description), we will also attend to questions about how we understand and constitute both “human beings” and “environment”: How “natural” is nature and how is it similar or different from “culture”?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>cv</title>
      <link>https://inadeqtfuturs.github.io/cv/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Feb 2017 08:43:15 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://inadeqtfuturs.github.io/cv/</guid>
      <description>Alex Christie Loyola University Chicago, Department of English 1032 West Sheridan Road // Chicago, IL 60660 alexj.christie [at] gmail.com   Education   2019 (Expected): PhD, English Literature Loyola University Chicago, Chicago IL Dissertation: inadequate futures, directed by Suzanne Bost    2014: MA, English Literature Loyola University Chicago, Chicago IL   2013: BA, English Literature; BA Philosophy Pennsylvania State University, State College PA Phi Beta Kappa     Teaching  Instructor of Record [Loyola University Chicago] 2018: Core Writing Seminar: Writing in the Contemporary (Spring) 2017: Nature in Literature: Human @ the Limit (Spring) 2016: Exploring Fiction: Remediating Narrative (Fall) 2016: Core Literature Seminar: Stranger Than Fiction (Spring) 2015: Core Writing Seminar: Writing in the Contemporary (Fall) 2014: Core Writing Seminar: Writing Responsibly (Fall)  Teaching Assistant [Loyola University Chicago]  2017: Contemporary Critical Theory (Fall) 2015: Contemporary Critical Theory (Spring) 2014: Core Writing Seminar: Writing Responsibly (Spring)   Tutoring &amp; High School Experience  2017: Expository and Academic Writing Summer Enrichment at Loyola - serving rising high school seniors 2013-14: Graduate Tutor Loyola Writing Center – serving undergraduates 2013: Graduate Tutor Loyola Literacy Center – serving Rogers Park Chicago area     Publications   2018: Review of Stacy Alaimo&#39;s Exposed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>teaching philosophy</title>
      <link>https://inadeqtfuturs.github.io/teaching/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Feb 2017 08:43:15 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://inadeqtfuturs.github.io/teaching/</guid>
      <description>Learning is dynamic and collaborative, requiring various participants and styles of participation. My teaching fosters critical engagement with and among various textual collaborators that enter the classroom by highlighting how texts ‘resonate’ when we interact with them. Borrowing the term from Wai Chee Dimock’s ‘A Theory of Resonance,’ I utilize the notion of resonance to emphasize that knowledge is not an object unilaterally disseminated by experts, but an unstable result of our relation to texts both fleshy and pulpy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>engl 273 - fall 2016</title>
      <link>https://inadeqtfuturs.github.io/syllabus/engl273/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jan 2017 17:11:43 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://inadeqtfuturs.github.io/syllabus/engl273/</guid>
      <description>engl 273: remediating narrative Fall 2016    Required Texts  Danielewski, The Familiar, Volume 1: One Rainy Day in May [978-0375714948] Markson, This is Not a Novel [978-1582431338] Nelson, The Red Parts [978-1555977368] Rankine, Don&amp;rsquo;t Let Me Be Lonely [978-1555974077] Ware, Building Stories [978-0375424335] [note: please do not buy this right away. wait until later in the semester]        Date: Reading:    week 1: introduction   8/29 Monday Course Intro, Stokes, ‘No, you’re not entitled to your opinion’   8/31 Wednesday Gallop, ‘The Ethics of Close Reading’   9/2 Friday Faulkner, &amp;lsquo;A Rose for Emily&amp;lsquo;        week 2: what might narrative do?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>engl 288 - spring 2017</title>
      <link>https://inadeqtfuturs.github.io/syllabus/engl288/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jan 2017 17:11:37 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://inadeqtfuturs.github.io/syllabus/engl288/</guid>
      <description>engl 288: human @ the limit Spring 2017    Required Texts  Coetzee, The Lives of Animals [978-0691070896 or 978-0691173900] Danielewski, The Familiar Vol 1: One Rainy Day in May [978-0375714948] Ishiguro, Never Let Me Go [978-1400078776] Yamashita, Through the Arc of the Rain Forest [978-0918273826]        Date: Reading:    week 1: introduction   1/17 Tuesday Course Intro, Gallop, ‘The Ethics of Close Reading,’ Spahr, &#39;Some of We and the Land That Was Never Ours&#39;   1/19 Thursday Stokes, &#39;No, You&#39;re Not Entitled to Your Opinion,&#39; Braidotti, The Posthuman, Intro &amp; Ch 1        week 2: into the rain forest   1/24 Tuesday Yamashita, Through the Arc of the Rain Forest pt.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ucwr 110 - spring 2018</title>
      <link>https://inadeqtfuturs.github.io/syllabus/ucwr110/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jan 2017 21:15:06 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://inadeqtfuturs.github.io/syllabus/ucwr110/</guid>
      <description>UCWR 110.003: Writing Responsibly Spring 2018    Course Description—“Writing in the Contemporary”: UCWR 110 is a rhetorically oriented reading and writing course in which you will analyze, evaluate, and produce both written and visual texts. This course builds on your preexisting writing and rhetorical skills—academic and otherwise—helping you become a critical reader and adept communicator. The writing and critical thinking skills honed during class are practiced in service of your time in and beyond Loyola.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>search</title>
      <link>https://inadeqtfuturs.github.io/search/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jan 2017 12:00:18 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://inadeqtfuturs.github.io/search/</guid>
      <description>     $(document).ready(function() { $(&#39;#tipue_search_input&#39;).tipuesearch({ &#39;mode&#39; : &#39;json&#39;, &#39;show&#39;: 10, &#39;contentLocation&#39;: &#39;{{ .Site.BaseURL }}/tipuesearch_content.json&#39; }); });     </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>