<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Culp on inadequate futures</title>
    <link>https://inadeqtfuturs.github.io/tags/culp/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Culp on inadequate futures</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 May 2017 08:23:51 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://inadeqtfuturs.github.io/tags/culp/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>[004 - negativity in Culp]</title>
      <link>https://inadeqtfuturs.github.io/post/004-negativity-in-culp/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 May 2017 08:23:51 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://inadeqtfuturs.github.io/post/004-negativity-in-culp/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m revisiting Andrew Culp&amp;rsquo;s &lt;i&gt;Dark Deleuze&lt;/i&gt; this week. My director suggested the book last summer somewhere between me reading &lt;i&gt;A Thousand Plateaus&lt;/i&gt; and Claire Colebrook&amp;rsquo;s &lt;i&gt;Death of the PostHuman&lt;/i&gt; as an example of a negative version of Deleuze that might help make sense of Colebrook&amp;rsquo;s work. In general, and this is the way I&amp;rsquo;ve always read D&amp;amp;G, &lt;i&gt;TP&lt;/i&gt; has always been this joyous and affirmative text riddled with &amp;lsquo;little monsters&amp;rsquo; for cultivating novel concepts (Culp 1). Each plateau offered something new&amp;mdash;a new concept, methodology, reading. In moments of lucidity (usually while reading and then never again) it feels very portable. Dark Deleuze, by comparison, is very different: &amp;lsquo;Emerging from scholars concerned with the condition of the present, the darkness refashions a revolutionary Deleuze: revolutionary negativity in a world characterized by compulsory happiness, decentralized control, and overexposure&amp;rsquo; (2). This struck me as odd for two reasons: first, all of my work is &amp;lsquo;concerned with the condition of the present,&amp;rsquo; so it seemed odd that I hadn&amp;rsquo;t encountered much of this scholarship. But second, and while I absolutely agree with Culp that the revolutionary concepts offered by Deleuze throughout his corpus&amp;mdash;&amp;lsquo;transversal lines, rhizomatic connections, compositionist networks, complex assemblages, affective experiences, and enchanted objects&amp;rsquo;&amp;mdash;had been largely integrated into public consciousness, it&amp;rsquo;s never occurred to me Deleuze&amp;rsquo;s work had run it&amp;rsquo;s course, cleaved into neoliberal-ese (7).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>