<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>That Winter the Wolf Came on inadequate futures</title>
    <link>https://inadeqtfuturs.github.io/tags/that-winter-the-wolf-came/</link>
    <description>Recent content in That Winter the Wolf Came on inadequate futures</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 04 Jun 2017 11:43:17 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://inadeqtfuturs.github.io/tags/that-winter-the-wolf-came/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>[006 - &lt;i&gt;That Winter the Wolf Came&lt;/i&gt;, autonomy, and climate]</title>
      <link>https://inadeqtfuturs.github.io/post/006-winter-the-wolf-came/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jun 2017 11:43:17 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://inadeqtfuturs.github.io/post/006-winter-the-wolf-came/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://inadeqtfuturs.github.io/images/cover-winter.jpg&#34; class=&#34;wide&#34; /&gt;
Juliana Spahr&amp;rsquo;s &lt;i&gt;That Winter the Wolf Came&lt;/i&gt; offers solace in a moment of ecological anxiety and disaster. As Trump pulls the U.S. out of the Paris Climate Accord (indeed, a largely symbolic act but with very real ecological, economic, and political ramifications), I&amp;rsquo;m struck by the right&amp;rsquo;s oxymoronic stance on the country&amp;rsquo;s autonomy, or the ability to be autonomous in an age of intensified globalization. It&amp;rsquo;s easy to see the tension between the way the nation-state holds open the door for transnational capital&amp;mdash;i.e. producing fluid borders rather than locking them down and securing the reproduction of a specific citizenry&amp;mdash;and the insistence that somehow the U.S. can stand alone, or dictate the terms by which its borders function. The travel ban, increased racist violence, and the dream of an economy sustained by coal all play into this fantasy of the autonomous nation, and by proxy the autonomous masculine figurehead Trump longs to become.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>