<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>House of Leaves on inadequate futures</title>
    <link>https://inadeqtfuturs.github.io/tags/house-of-leaves/</link>
    <description>Recent content in House of Leaves on inadequate futures</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 23 Sep 2017 10:57:47 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://inadeqtfuturs.github.io/tags/house-of-leaves/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>[008 - the novel as inhuman]</title>
      <link>https://inadeqtfuturs.github.io/post/008-novel-as-inhuman/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Sep 2017 10:57:47 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://inadeqtfuturs.github.io/post/008-novel-as-inhuman/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My current project/chapter has me returning to Mark Z. Danielewski&amp;rsquo;s work, a novelist who&amp;rsquo;s been with me since I first thought about teaching, and latter became an important fixture for how I think about literature, and then, again, latter, became an even &lt;i&gt;more&lt;/i&gt; important figure for how I think about ethics, (non)humans, and so much more. Although the chapter is specifically interested in inter-weaving Danielewski&amp;rsquo;s most recent set of novels, collectively known as &lt;i&gt;The &lt;font color=&#34;#f9b9d2&#34;&gt;Familiar&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/i&gt;, into contemporary posthumanism, figuring &lt;i&gt;The &lt;font color=&#34;#f9b9d2&#34;&gt;Familiar&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/i&gt; as another resource for theorizing relationality among (non)humans, it&amp;rsquo;s also given me a chance to revisit his work as a whole. Specifically, I&amp;rsquo;m looking at some of the &amp;lsquo;paratextual&amp;rsquo; (if you can call it that) projects surrounding &lt;i&gt;The &lt;font color=&#34;#f9b9d2&#34;&gt;Familiar&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/i&gt; including a talk that later became an article called &amp;lsquo;Parable No. 9: The Hopeless Animal and the End of Nature.&amp;rsquo; Given in Cologne, Germany in the Fall of 2010, the talk catalyzed my interest in posthumanism, actor network theory, and speculative realism (though I&amp;rsquo;ve largely abandoned the latter two in favor of the former), and continues to inform how I think about hope and our relation to animals. By that same token, I&amp;rsquo;m hoping that &amp;lsquo;Parable No. 9&amp;rsquo; will offer insight into Danielewski&amp;rsquo;s novels&amp;mdash;there&amp;rsquo;s clearly cross-contamination&amp;mdash;as well as provide fodder for positioning his work among other posthuman theorists.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>